janrainsso.com 2014-12-24

# Janrain Privacy Statement | Janrain

Effective as of April 2, 2013.

Welcome to this Janrain, Inc. (“Janrain”) website. Janrain provides a software-as-a-service customer profile management platform with solutions for registration, social login, social sharing, single sign on, and profile data storage to help our customers increase user acquisition and engagement on their websites and mobile apps.  As a leading provider of these customer profile management solutions, we at Janrain are committed to protecting the privacy of individuals who visit our website and individuals whose personal information we may receive through the use of the Janrain Customer Identity Management Platform and related services provided to our customers.

This privacy statement describes our practices regarding the personal information we collect on and through our websites which link to this privacy statement.  This privacy statement also describes – under the heading, Customer Data – our role and practices in connection with personal information we may host on behalf of our SaaS customers.

As a visitor to this website, your privacy remains under your control.  We want you to have the information you need to make your own decisions regarding your privacy in the context of your interaction with Janrain websites.

Janrain abides by the Safe Harbor Frameworks developed by the U.S. Department of Commerce and (1) the European Union and (2) Switzerland, respectively.  We have certified that we adhere to the related Safe Harbor Privacy Principles. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Janrain’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

  1. [Web Sites Covered](http://janrain.com/janrain-privacy-statement/#websites-covered)
  2. [Consent](http://janrain.com/janrain-privacy-statement/#consent)
  3. [Personal Information We Collect](http://janrain.com/janrain-privacy-statement/#personal-information)
  4. [Use of Personal Information Collected](http://janrain.com/janrain-privacy-statement/#personal-information-collected)
  5. [Sharing of Personal Information Collected](http://janrain.com/janrain-privacy-statement/#sharing-personal-information)
  6. [Choices and Communication Preferences](http://janrain.com/janrain-privacy-statement/#choices-and-communication)
  7. [Security](http://janrain.com/janrain-privacy-statement/#security)
  8. [Customer Data](http://janrain.com/janrain-privacy-statement/#customer-data)
  9. [Children](http://janrain.com/janrain-privacy-statement/#children)
  10. [Correcting and updating your information](http://janrain.com/janrain-privacy-statement/#correcting)
  11. [Changes to this Privacy Statement](http://janrain.com/janrain-privacy-statement/#changes)
  12. [Contacting Us](http://janrain.com/janrain-privacy-statement/#contact)

* * *

### 1\.  Web Sites Covered

This Privacy Statement covers the information practices of Janrain websites sites that link to this Privacy Statement, including [http://www.janrain.com](http://www.janrain.com/); <http://janrain.com/>; <http://trust.janrain.com/>; <https://rpxnow.com/privacy>; and <https://janraincapture.com/>.  These websites are hosted in the United States.

Our websites may contain links to non-Janrain websites. We are not responsible for the information practices or the content of such other websites. We invite you to review the privacy statements of those other websites to understand their information practices.

### 2.  Consent

By providing personal information to our websites, you consent to its use in accordance with this Privacy Statement and, if you live outside the U.S., you consent to the transfer of such information to the U.S.

### 3\.  Personal Information We Collect

  * **Information You Give Us**

We receive and store any information you enter on our Web site or give us in any other way.  This information may include (a) your name, email address, and other personal information; (b) your interaction with website features; (c) transaction-related information, such as, when you download software from us; and (d) information you provide us when you contact us for assistance.

  * **Information We Collect Automatically and Cookies**

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with our website.  For example, like many websites, our Janrain.com website uses “cookies”: We set a cookie for every user who visits our Janrain.com website. This initiates an anonymous browsing record until a visitor fills out a form (at janrain.com or developers.janrain.com) at which point we match the visitor’s anonymous record to an identifiable visitor using the information the visitor provided by filling out the form.  We also gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

### 4\.  Use of Personal Information Collected

We may use your information (a) to deliver our website services and features desired by you (including any customization features requested by you), (b) to improve our services for you, (c) to personalize content and offers that may be of interest to you, (d) to respond to your inquiries, and (e) to fulfill your request for products or services.  If provided, we may use your email address to contact you from time to time.

Cookies allow us to store and retrieve login information on a user’s system. They provide us with data that we can use to improve the quality of our website and make it easier to use.

We use information gathered automatically and stored in log files to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.  For example, we may use the non-personally identifiable information, like your IP address, to statistically analyze site usage and to customize our site’s content, layout and services. The resulting information will allow us to improve our services and better understand and serve our website users.

### 5\.  Sharing of Personal Information Collected

We share information that identifies you only as described below and with subsidiaries we control that follow the same practices described in this Privacy Statement.

  * **Third Party Service Providers** : We may retain other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf, such as sending email, removing repetitive and inaccurate information from customer lists, analyzing data, processing credit cards, and providing marketing assistance.   They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.
  * **Protecting Others and Ourselves** : We will disclose your personally identifiable information if we believe disclosure is necessary to comply with the law or to protect our rights, property, or safety, our customer, or others. In particular, we may cooperate with law enforcement agencies in any official investigation and disclose your personally identifiable information to the relevant agency in doing so.
  * **Business Transfer** : We reserve the right to transfer your personal information in the event Janrain, Inc. or substantially all of our assets are acquired.
  * **With Your Consent** : Other than as stated above, we will not disclose or provide your personal information to a third party without your explicit consent for us to do so.

### 6\.  Choices and Communication Preferences

  * As a visitor to our website you can always choose not to provide us with personal information when requested, although it may be required for you to take full advantage of our website offerings.
  * If your browser is not already set up to refuse cookies, you can configure your browser to refuse them.  By doing so you may not be able to take full advantage of our website features.
  *  You may manage your receipt of marketing and non-transactional communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of our marketing emails.  Additionally, you may specify your communications preferences at <http://www1.janrain.com/UnsubscribePage.html>.  Customers, however, cannot opt out of receiving transactional emails related to their account.

### 7\.  Security

Janrain uses a secure infrastructure, industry standard technology, and appropriate technical and operational safeguards designed to protect the security, confidentiality, and integrity of data submitted to Janrain. The security of your personal information also depends on your protection of your account. Please do not disclose your website login credentials to unauthorized people. Also, be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. If you have any other questions about the security of our websites, please contact us using the contact information provided below in the “Contacting Us” section.

### 8\.  Customer Data

**\- Observance of Safe Harbor Principles**

As mentioned at the beginning of this Privacy Statement, we offer our customers a software-as-a-service (“SaaS”) customer profile management platform and abide by the U.S. – EU and U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks for protecting the privacy of data flowing from the EU and Switzerland to the United States.  As a processor of personal information on behalf of our customers, we observe the Safe Harbor Principles, several of which are discussed below.

Notice and Choice:  Individuals may submit personal information to our customers through the use of the website registration and login services we provide to our customers. (Some of these services may have a notice that they are “powered by Janrain”). This personal information is submitted with notice to, and the consent of, the individual user via identity providers’ permission screens, or voluntarily provided by the user at registration. Once Janrain has successfully facilitated the transmission of personal information to a customer’s database that is not hosted by Janrain, it is that customer’s responsibility to guard any the personal information against unauthorized access or transmission.

Our Role Processing and Protecting Customer Data: As part of our Janrain Customer Identity Management Platform™, we may receive and host on our customers’ behalf such personal information and other data a customer may provide to us for hosting (collectively, “Customer Data”). Our customers are the data controllers of Customer Data. As the processors of personal information on behalf of our customers, we follow their instructions with respect to the information they control. In doing so, we implement appropriate technical, physical and administrative measures against unauthorized processing of such information and against loss, destruction of, or damage to, personal information. We do not determine how our customers use Customer Data, and we will not access or disclose it except as directed by our customers or required by law.

Accessing, Correcting, Amending, or Deleting Personal Information: If you are an individual seeking access to, or who would like to correct, amend, or delete your personal information which Janrain may be storing on behalf of our customer, you should direct your request to the applicable Janrain customer acting as the data controller for such information. Customers may access and delete Customer Data, including an individual record, via an application provider interface or API. Following the deletion of personal information in a database we host, the related backup data will be deleted, generally within 30 days.

**\- Cookies Related to Our Social Login Service**

The following table shows how cookies are placed on user browsers in connection with our Social Login service.  Each is required to deliver critical functionality or complete the users’ service requests.

**Type** | **Cookie Name** | **Created** | **Stored Data** | **Usage**  
---|---|---|---|---  
**Session** | login_tab | When the user clicks on a social sign-in link | Identity provider name or identifier | Records which identity provider has been selected by the user, for use during the transaction  
**Session** | expected_tab | After a successful social sign-in transaction | Identity provider name or identifier | Records which identity provider has successfully authenticated the user, for use during the transaction  
**Permanent** | welcome_info_name | After a successful social sign-in transaction | Display name of user as returned by identity provider | Retrieves a display name for providing visual confirmation to end user  
  
An individual using our Single Sign On service will have three cookies placed on his or her browser: session_id; visited; and janrain_sso_checked <domainspecifier>. These cookies are required to enable the service.

**\- Anonymous Statistics**

To assist our customers and partners and to market our services, we may disclose anonymous, aggregated, statistical information related to the use of our services by many or all of our customers.  Such information will not contain any personal information or identify any customer or user of our services.

### 9\.  Children

We do not sell our services to children and children are not eligible to use our websites. If we learn that somehow personal information from a child under 13 has been collected on or through our website, we will delete the information.

### 10\. Correcting and updating your information

If you purchase a service from our website and create an account, you may later update your information on the service dashboard. To update Billing Information you can contact our Finance department or submit a ticket to support.janrain.com.

### 11.  Changes to this Privacy Statement

From time to time we may update this Privacy Statement.  If we do, we will update the “effective date” at the top of the Privacy Statement. If we make an update with changes that are materially less restrictive regarding our use and disclosure of your information, we will provide prior notice of such changes by posting notice on our website at the top of the then current Privacy Statement 30 days before the effective date of the update. You should visit this page periodically to review any such changes to the Privacy Statement. Your continued use of this website or our service and/or continued provision of information to us will be subject to the terms of the then-current Privacy Statement.

### 12.  Contacting Us

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Statement or about the privacy practices of Janrain, please contact us by email at [privacy@janrain.com](mailto:privacy@janrain.com) or by mail at Janrain, Inc.

_Attn: VP of Legal and Privacy_  
519 SW 3rd Ave., Suite 200  
Portland, OR 97204
